#### Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/sathish-kumar-k-k-25851539 (LinkedIn)

# Top Skills

JSON Web Token (JWT)

**OAuth** 

Application Programming Interfaces (API)

# Languages

French (Elementary)

English (Professional Working)

Tamil (Professional Working)

Hindi (Elementary)

#### Certifications

AMCAT Certified Data Processing Specialist

AMCAT Certified in English Comprehension

**Python Basics** 

### Honors-Awards

Livewire Award

Livewire

Rain Maker

Rain Maker

SOCH -2022 Innovation Jam Contest - Winning GOLD Status

#### **Publications**

Full Duplex Communication Using Java Websocket

# SATHISH KUMAR K K

Al Engineer | Senior Java Full Stack Engineer | Product Advisor | Product Solutioning | Al Solutioning | Cloud Solutioning | DevOps | Solace | Microservices | React.js | Angular | TDD | DDD Chennai, Tamil Nadu, India

# Summary

I am a passionate, Java Full Stack developer with overall 14 years of experience in Java development and Cloud, covering multiple technologies. I keep myself updated and can adapt quickly to new coding conventions. I am good at working independently or in a close team environment and apply a positive attitude to every task I undertake. Also seeking in to the world of Blockchain, ML, NLP, GenAI, Solid protocol for data privacy

https://teams.microsoft.com/l/meetupjoin/19%3ameeting\_YTJIYjQ1MWMtZjI2MC00Mzk5LThiNTctODdINTJmN %40thread.v2/0?context=%7b%22Tid%22%3a %2293f33571-550f-43cf-b09f-cd331338d086%22%2c%22Oid %22%3a%224c099197-5cfb-42b9-ae31-4547340cada0%22%7d

# Experience

Luxoft India

Lead Engineer

February 2023 - Present (2 years 5 months)

Chennai, Tamil Nadu, India

Client Name: Standard Chartered

Description:

MAR (Market Abuse Regulation) is a project which is used to monitor market abuse to identify any fraud in trade, generate UI alerts. For achieving this, we have developed microservice applications and the core module is SDP (Surveillance Data parser), where this will gather the data from Upstream as either xml file or excel file and generate the common template file format as csv. The generated csv file will be ingested to FD (First Derivative). After completion of ingestion the UI module will take the data of SDP output file, they will generate the alerts.

Responsibilities involved:

- Migration from Java 8 to Java 17 along with Spring upgrade.
- Nexus and Sonar Vulnerability remediation.
- Developed a cloud-based application that is highly available and fault tolerant
- Developed a full stack web application from scratch, including back-end services, front-end interface, and database
- Developed a full-stack web application that handled concurrent users with minimal downtime
- Developed a full stack web application with a modern user interface that improved user engagement.
- Implemented Solace Queues Client subscription logic based on SMF
   Protocol (Solace Messaging Format) to enable asynchronous communication
   between upstream and downstream and also improving system scalability and
   decoupling processes.

#### IBM

Senior System Analyst April 2019 - February 2023 (3 years 11 months) Chennai, Tamil Nadu, India

Client Name: United Parcel Service

Worked as "Application Developer for Red Hat Openshift Cloud Microservices, Migration & Modernization".

USP is a Global parcel service company and the application that I worked is to give detailed idea of the package status.

# Cognizant

Associate

January 2016 - April 2019 (3 years 4 months)

Chennai Area, India

J.B. Hunt is a trucking and transportation company. Here in Cognizant we do Technology upgrade from Mainframe to Java. The Project is divided into four Development Tracks like Order Capture, Qualify, Consolidation, and Confirmation. I am working under Qualify Track. Qualify is a core part, where rules are configured in separate domain and those rules are fetched based on Order characteristics to qualify the order. Based on the qualification rule run result, qualify system will decide either order to be Accepted or new Opportunity to be created for the same order.

#### Responsibilities:

- Documented High Level and Low Level Design for the given Use Case.
- Engaged in HLD and LLD discussion with Client.
- Prepared Reference Projects for various technologies and APIs that we used.
- Transformed Businesses in use case to LLD and then to the Actual working java code.
- Exposed micro-services, that to be consumed by UI and other Modules.

#### **HCLTech**

3 years 6 months

#### Rockyroad

August 2014 - December 2016 (2 years 5 months)

Chennai Area, India

The project is a product engineering project and details are confidential, the main objective of the project was to develop a new product with new innovative idea for the client. Project included different teams for product engineering; I was part of the middleware team. The middleware team had to develop an event based client - server bidirectional communication to facilitate live information feed. This will be used as a middleware for any live communication between any clients.

### SWA ATOM Replacement

July 2013 - August 2014 (1 year 2 months)

The goal of this application is to take care of the Training Planning and Scheduling of Pilots to make them eligible to fly. The purpose is to provide the Training schedulers the appropriate information on the qualifications required by trainings completed by each of the Pilots. As a business rule, each position held by Pilot require proof of acquired knowledge and training requirements in accordance with Regulatory and Training Curriculum as defined by Flight Aviation Administration (FAA).

Parthys Reverse Informatics Analytic Solutions Pvt. Ltd.

2 years 11 months

#### GlialMine

June 2011 - July 2013 (2 years 2 months)

Chennai Area, India

Client : Tuffs University

Team Size: 2

Description

The GlialMine is a web based product containing the biological related data. One can search and query the database for particular gene or protein and its functions. It has an efficient construction and querying of large database (production database currently>0.5TB). Data can be exported in all common formats. Generating, uploading and working with lists of genes and providing embedded tools with which to characterize them. E.g. finding publications that mention an unexpectedly large number of genes in a list, or finding enriched Gene Ontology terms. It maintains Private workspaces for all individual users to save their own search queries and list. Configuration of much of user interface by biologist super-user rather than developers.

#### Roles & Responsibilities

Deputed at the clients place carried out various roles as a java Developer to support and deliver the interface related activities for supporting biological applications.

Development of new functionalities for GlialMine.

Enhancement of existing Functionalities for GlialMine.

Troubleshooting for all the above mentioned modules during the SIT/UAT Cycles.

Creating new User Reports/Downloads for end Customer requirements. Involved in production implementations.

#### **Technical Environment**

Core Java, JSP, Java Script, GitHub, Ubuntu,XML

Management Information System report September 2010 - July 2013 (2 years 11 months)

Customer: Internal project

Team Size: 3

#### Description

MIS or Management Information System is a computer based system used by organizations for transforming data into useful information for better Decision Making. It helps management make better plans and provide the way to implement.

MIS report is monthly report that submit to the Head of the unit ,this report should reach to the HR from all the Department Heads on first week of every month.

MIS is used for generating project status reports, performance report, requirements details and employee details. Each employee submits a report

of the activity that has been done during the day. This helps to analyze the productivity of an employee, of a department and the organization as a whole.

Roles & Responsibilities

To design and develop project status reports module, performance report module.

To build an error free application.

Bug fixing and unit testing.

Reporting to team lead and documentation.

**Technical Environment** 

Java1.7 Struts 2.2.1, Hibernate 3, Jquery1.7, MySQL5, Tomcat Server7, Eclipse

Cation Tool

December 2010 - October 2011 (11 months)

Customer: Internal project

Team Size: 2

### Description

Cation is a web based application, which uses to store reaction equations into the database. In this it involves serious of conditional to check before the data enters into database. Thus creating database for all possible type of chemical reactions.

And also each activity of a worker in this tool is logged and maintained as a history, which will be considered while at the time of employee appraisal.

Roles & Responsibilities

Understanding the requirement.

Develop and Design the application.

Getting assistance form the; achieving business goals in addition to the enhancement and bug fixing.

Configuring Tomcat Server.

Deploy the application in server.

Unite testing.

Reporting to project lead.

**Technical Environment** 

Java Struts 2, Jquery, MySQL, Tomcat Server, Eclipse

# Education

## NIIT

Deploma in Java, Java · (2011 - 2011)

Erode Sengunthar Engineering College
Bachelor of Engineering (B.E.), Electronics and Instrumentation
Engineering · (April 2006 - March 2010)

Reliance Metric Higher secondary School 11th and 12th, Computer Science · (2004 - 2006)

SSM Metric Higher Secondary School 10th, State Board · (1992 - 2003)